<strings>

    <string id="str_culture_description.german" text="{=E17HRE_desc}In 1700, the German people lived within the fragmented mosaic of the Holy Roman Empire, a decentralized collection of hundreds of sovereign principalities, free cities, and ecclesiastical territories. This era was defined by the long recovery from the Thirty Years' War and a rigid social hierarchy where the peasantry remained largely tied to the land under feudal obligations. While the Empire provided a shared cultural and linguistic framework, the population was deeply divided by the cuius regio, eius religio principle, which split the German lands between a Catholic south and west and a Protestant north and east. The year 1700 marked a significant political shift as Prussia prepared to elevate itself to a kingdom in 1701, signaling its rise as a rival to the Austrian Habsburgs. Culturally, the German people were on the cusp of the Baroque height and the early Enlightenment, with urban centers like Hamburg, Leipzig, and Vienna serving as burgeoning hubs for music, printing, and the intellectual debates that would eventually forge a more unified national identity." />
    <string id="str_adjective_for_culture.german" text="{=E17HRE_adj_cul}German" />
    <string id="str_culture_rich_name.german" text="{=E17HRE_cul_name}German" />
    <string id="str_faction_ruler_name_with_title.german" text="{=E17HRE_ruler_title}{?RULER.GENDER}Empress{?}Emperor{\?} {RULER.NAME}" />
    <string id="str_faction_noble_name_with_title.german" text="{=E17HRE_noble_title}{?RULER.GENDER}Lady{?}Lord{\?} {RULER.NAME}" />
    <string id="str_faction_official.german" text="{=E17HRE_noble_m}Lord" />
    <string id="str_faction_official.german_f" text="{=E17HRE_noble_f}Lady" />
    <string id="str_faction_ruler.german" text="{=E17HRE_ruler_m}Emperor" />
    <string id="str_faction_ruler.german_f" text="{=E17HRE_ruler_f}Empress" />
    <string id="str_faction_ruler_term_in_speech.german" text="{=E17HRE_ruler_sp}{?RULER.GENDER}Empress{?}Emperor{\?} {RULER.NAME}" />
    <string id="str_neutral_term_for_culture.german" text="{=E17HRE_n_cul}german" />
    <string id="str_adjective_for_faction.german" text="{=E17HRE_adj_fac}Germans" />
    <string id="str_short_term_for_faction.german" text="{=E17HRE_short_term}Germany" />
    <string id="str_faction_formal_name_for_culture.german" text="{=E17HRE_formal_name}Holy Roman Empire" />
    <string id="str_faction_informal_name_for_culture.german" text="{=E17HRE_informal_name}German" />
	
	</strings>