<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<base xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" type="string">
 <strings>
  <string id="776J8Fng" text="Baldimos"/>
  <string id="X7Xp9xGe" text="Tertha"/>
  <string id="str_adjective_for_culture.vlandia.text" text="Osrickin"/>
  <string id="str_culture_rich_name.vlandia.text" text="Osrickin"/>
  <string id="str_neutral_term_for_culture.vlandia.text" text="Osrickin"/>
  <string id="str_adjective_for_faction.vlandia.text" text="Osrickin"/>
  <string id="str_short_term_for_faction.vlandia.text" text="Osrickin"/>
  <string id="str_faction_formal_name_for_culture.vlandia.text" text="The Osrickin"/>
  <string id="str_faction_informal_name_for_culture.vlandia.text" text="the Osrickin"/>
  <string id="bk_descriptionn_vlandia" text="Claiming themselves the descendants of Osric Iron-Arm, the Osrickin are one the largest Wilunding tribes that migrated from west-over-seas. Among the original tribes, the Osrickin hold the greatest sway, represented by Derthert dey Meroc, who styles himself 'King of all the Wilunding' - a comfortable lie. Theirs is also the tradition of horsemanship and gallantry, which they hold highest amongst the original tribes. The Osrickin, having consolidated power over the Calradoi, were at the vanguard of reorganizing their kingdom into a feudal, organized structure, rather than a confederation of squabbling tribes. Such ideas were taken from the conquered Calradoi institutions and nobility, many of whom intermarried with the newly-settling Wilunding families - an easier choice than being butchered. Such mixing created a culture and language distinctively divergent from their original Wilunding origins. For relegating the other tribes to inferior positions, as well as their increasingly Calradoi-like tendencies, other Wilunding tribes accuse the Osrickin of betraying tradition, and claim their lineage a farse."/>
  <string id="str_adjective_for_culture.swadia.text" text="Swadisch"/>
  <string id="str_culture_rich_name.swadia.text" text="Swadisch"/>
  <string id="str_neutral_term_for_culture.swadia.text" text="Swadisch"/>
  <string id="str_adjective_for_faction.swadia.text" text="Swadisch"/>
  <string id="str_short_term_for_faction.swadia.text" text="Swadisch"/>
  <string id="str_faction_formal_name_for_culture.swadia.text" text="The Swadisch"/>
  <string id="str_faction_informal_name_for_culture.swadia.text" text="the Swadisch"/>
  <string id="str_culture_description.swadia.text" text="The second largest Wilunding tribe to settle in Western Calradia, the Swadisch have marked their presence ever since the first Wilunding incursions. Among the notable Wilunding warlords counts Oca, a patron of Swadisch belief and tradition. The Swadisch respect rulership, but value their autonomy: to be lord or lady of his or her castle is what every Swadisch desires, for they distinctively do not discriminate women as family heads. Horsemanship is at the core of their tradition, as in most Wilunding cultures, as well as industriousness: Swadisch craftsmen find no match among other tribes. Many among the Swadisch nobility feel repressed by their Osrickin overlords, causing many a revolt in hopes of increased Swadisch influence."/>
  <string id="str_adjective_for_culture.rhodok.text" text="Rhodok"/>
  <string id="str_culture_rich_name.rhodok.text" text="Rhodok"/>
  <string id="str_neutral_term_for_culture.rhodok.text" text="Rhodok"/>
  <string id="str_adjective_for_faction.rhodok.text" text="Rhodok"/>
  <string id="str_short_term_for_faction.rhodok.text" text="Rhodoks"/>
  <string id="str_faction_formal_name_for_culture.rhodok.text" text="The Rhodoks"/>
  <string id="str_faction_informal_name_for_culture.rhodok.text" text="the Rhodoks"/>
  <string id="str_culture_description.rhodok.text" text="Hailing from west-over-seas, the Rhodok count amongst the Wilunding tribes that settled in Western Calradia, though the least influential of them. Few Rhodok families were granted sizable holdings, and none of the original warlords count amongst the Rhodok. Of all other Wilunding tribes, the Swadisch are who they share most kinship. Swadisch and Rhodok often work in tandem, though that usually means the Swadisch lead, and the Rhodok follow. Unlike most Wilunding, the Rhodok hold no particular love for horsemanship, a custom others find queer. Nevertheless, though not numerous, the Rhodok craftsmanship is hold at high regards, specially that of wine and foodstuffs, and their warriors are known to fight with savagery. Above all the Rhodok value freedom: to farm, make industry, profit, and to choose their rulers. For Rhodoks despise the idea of blood inheritance, and instead believe in merit, as their god Kronvalt taught them."/>
  <string id="str_adjective_for_culture.balion.text" text="Balionian"/>
  <string id="str_culture_rich_name.balion.text" text="Balionian"/>
  <string id="str_neutral_term_for_culture.balion.text" text="Balion"/>
  <string id="str_adjective_for_faction.balion.text" text="Balionian"/>
  <string id="str_short_term_for_faction.balion.text" text="Balionians"/>
  <string id="str_faction_formal_name_for_culture.balion.text" text="The Balionians"/>
  <string id="str_faction_informal_name_for_culture.balion.text" text="the Balionians"/>
  <string id="str_culture_description.balion.text" text="Balion is the land from whence the Wilunding came: the kingdom of west-over-seas. Many Wilunding tribes left their home for the prospect of more bountiful land, leaving much of Balion uninhabited. Of these, the largest are: the Osrickin, the Swadisch, the Rhodok and the Massa. However, the Island-Kingdom still reaches Calradia through trade connections and occasional adventurers. Many a sellsword also find work within Calradia: the settled Wilunding lords oft turn to these for support in their infighting, for they know the Balionians are too few to take their land. Though the Balionians worship older gods, in Calradia they are quick to adopt the local Wilunding gods, as these share much in tradition with their homeland. One could think of the Balionian as the tradition that binds all the Wilunding, unbesmirched by Calradia."/>
  <string id="str_adjective_for_culture.massa.text" text="Massa"/>
  <string id="str_culture_rich_name.massa.text" text="Massa"/>
  <string id="str_neutral_term_for_culture.massa.text" text="Massa"/>
  <string id="str_adjective_for_faction.massa.text" text="Massa"/>
  <string id="str_short_term_for_faction.massa.text" text="Massa"/>
  <string id="str_faction_formal_name_for_culture.massa.text" text="The Massa"/>
  <string id="str_faction_informal_name_for_culture.massa.text" text="the Massa"/>
  <string id="str_culture_description.massa.text" text="The Massa were once one of the largest if lowliest of Wilunding tribes. They were among the first wave of invaders into the Calradian west. Naturally nomadic shepherds, they never took to “Vlandian” settlement under the Imperial yoke. Penalised for grazing their flocks on feudal land, the Massa bitterly refused to give up their old ways. When the Osrickin revolted against the Calradians, the Massa were at the forefront. Their devotion to religious devastation made them among the most feared of the rebel tribes. They slaughtered cities wholesale and ransacked vast tracts of agricultural land. Although their dialect and people did in fact merge with Rhodok and Swadian settlers in the newly formed Vlandia, many Massa simply wandered onwards. Thus they gathered in their last great migration, and rode the sea southwards, to a densely wooded peninsula they call Ansiwe Fragifts: Gift of the Gods. A land ripe with both fruit and disease, inhabited by beasts and the Widugauja - native tribes with no kingdom to speak of."/>
  <string id="str_adjective_for_culture.empire.text" text="Calradicós"/>
  <string id="str_culture_rich_name.empire.text" text="Calradoi"/>
  <string id="str_neutral_term_for_culture.empire.text" text="Calradoi"/>
  <string id="str_adjective_for_faction.empire.text" text="Calradoi"/>
  <string id="str_short_term_for_faction.empire.text" text="Calradian"/>
  <string id="str_faction_formal_name_for_culture.empire.text" text="The Calradoi"/>
  <string id="str_faction_informal_name_for_culture.empire.text" text="the Calradoi"/>
  <string id="str_culture_description.empire.text" text="The Calradoi are the people of the Empire, though by now they have given their name to the entire continent which they dominate. A thousand years ago, they were an undistinguished tribe living in the hill country between the southern sea and the Battanian woods. One tradition set them apart from their neighbors - the Calradoi had no kings. Their citizenry has always taken an intense interest in the art of self-government, the balance between protecting the liberty of individuals and the needs of the state. Perhaps this is why they had a slight edge in the endless wars between one town and another, keeping armies in the field just a little longer, bouncing back just a little more quickly from a defeat. Some of their neighbors federated with them; others were overrun. Eventually the Calradoi formed an empire, which evolved into a monarchy in all but name. Their leaders are no longer distinguished civic elders but great landholders scattered across the continent; the striking force of their armies is no longer citizen-infantry but heavily armored cataphracts in the retinues of the wealthy. But they still take their civic traditions very seriously, believing that the Calradian ideal can unite a continent in peace, if only the ”barbarians” beyond their borders would agree to submit to it."/>
  <string id="str_adjective_for_culture.battania.text" text="Battaneid"/>
  <string id="str_culture_rich_name.battania.text" text="Battaniaid"/>
  <string id="str_neutral_term_for_culture.battania.text" text="Battaniaid"/>
  <string id="str_adjective_for_faction.battania.text" text="Battaniaid"/>
  <string id="str_short_term_for_faction.battania.text" text="Battaneid"/>
  <string id="str_faction_formal_name_for_culture.battania.text" text="The Battaniaid"/>
  <string id="str_faction_informal_name_for_culture.battania.text" text="the Battaniaid"/>
  <string id="str_culture_description.battania.text" text="The misty hills of north-western Calradia are dominated by the Battaniaid clans, the original inhabitants of much of the continent. Here they still practice their old beliefs: heroes of yore, river nymphs and sacred lakes that are portals to the divine world, such are the beliefs passed on by the Battaneid druids for generations. Their hilltop fortresses have born witness to countless wars fought to resist outside invaders: first the Empire's legions, and more recently the rising Sturgiski and Wilunding kingdoms. The Battaniaid clans often fought each other, each declaring themselves kings of their glen and hill. Yet, with the advent of such neighboring kingdoms, the clans have organized themselves into a high-kingdom: rather than various independent kings, now each king swears fealty to a high-king. Though this system can not satisfy every of their kings, the elected high-kings have preserved what little land the Battanaidd hold still. In addition, the Battanaidd are masters of the longbow, the night raid, the sudden wild charge out of the woods. They idolise valour, but especially like it when mixed with a bit of mischief - the cattle thief who can whisk an entire herd into the fog; the champion who dines with a rival tribe, and, regaling his hosts with an anecdote of battle, produces from his bag the skull of one of their kinsmen that he took as a souvenir."/>
  <string id="str_adjective_for_culture.aserai.text" text="Nahasawi"/>
  <string id="str_culture_rich_name.aserai.text" text="Nahasawi"/>
  <string id="str_neutral_term_for_culture.aserai.text" text="Nahasawi"/>
  <string id="str_adjective_for_faction.aserai.text" text="Nahasawi"/>
  <string id="str_short_term_for_faction.aserai.text" text="Nahasawi"/>
  <string id="str_faction_formal_name_for_culture.aserai.text" text="The Nahasawi"/>
  <string id="str_faction_informal_name_for_culture.aserai.text" text="the Nahasawi"/>
  <string id="str_culture_description.aserai.text" text="Natural to the Nahasa desert, the Nahasawi are a mixture of nomadic desert roamers and settled oasis farmers. Theirs are the traditions of horsemanship and camelry, both vital for trading along the many Nahasa routes. Among other cultures, the Nahasawi are known as unequal traders - it is said they never take a trade which is not in their advantage. The Nahasawi also come from a long tradition of poetry, scholarship and medicine: much like coin, they seek to acquire knowledge from far and wide. Each clan is fiercely proud of their lineage and often jealous of the others, yet they are a force to be reckoned with when united through a strong leader. Though they have not founded any cities themselves, the Nahasawi now rule over many great cities, taken both from Kannic and Siri, peoples that still hold the Nahasawi in low regard. Rather than spread out clans, the Nahasawi are now organized in a Sultanate - a system where being rich is almost the same as being legitimate. Their recent conquests, formerly Kannic cities across the sealine, were taken from the Calradoi, who lost their influence in the sourthern shores of the Jade Sea, which the Nahasawi call the Bahr al-Yeshm. An irony of history, for the Nahasawi clansmen oft served the legions as scouts, guides and ally cavalry against the Kannic."/>
  <string id="str_adjective_for_culture.khuzait.text" text="Devseg"/>
  <string id="str_culture_rich_name.khuzait.text" text="Devseglar"/>
  <string id="str_neutral_term_for_culture.khuzait.text" text="Devseglar"/>
  <string id="str_adjective_for_faction.khuzait.text" text="Devseglar"/>
  <string id="str_short_term_for_faction.khuzait.text" text="Devseg"/>
  <string id="str_faction_formal_name_for_culture.khuzait.text" text="The Devseglar"/>
  <string id="str_faction_informal_name_for_culture.khuzait.text" text="the Devseglar"/>
  <string id="str_culture_description.khuzait.text" text="Devseglar hail from the great grass steppes east of the Sulan Daglar. For generations their presence in the continent was that of raiding parties, content to returning to their homelands, where they lived as nomads. Two generations ago, Urkhun the Great united the Devseglar, and brought his horde upon the eastern Calradoi frontier. He was also known the Khuzait, the name other peoples call the Devseglar. In the former Calradoi lands, they conquered towns and settled in them, no longer roaming the steppes, and instead making their farms and homes within their new domain. Yet the tribes of the Khuzait confederacy still retain many of their nomadic traditions, and felt yurt tents stand next to mud-brick towers in settlements that are half-village, half-encampment. Many were butchered by the Devseglar, but many others instead spared: their khans have integrated locals within the khanate without bloodshed, regardless of their traditions, so long they pay tribute and serve the khanate."/>
  <string id="str_adjective_for_culture.sturgia.text" text="Sturgiskyy"/>
  <string id="str_culture_rich_name.sturgia.text" text="Sturgiskyy"/>
  <string id="str_neutral_term_for_culture.sturgia.text" text="Sturgiski"/>
  <string id="str_adjective_for_faction.sturgia.text" text="Sturgiski"/>
  <string id="str_short_term_for_faction.sturgia.text" text="Sturgiskyy"/>
  <string id="str_faction_formal_name_for_culture.sturgia.text" text="The Sturgiski"/>
  <string id="str_faction_informal_name_for_culture.sturgia.text" text="the Sturgiski"/>
  <string id="str_culture_description.sturgia.text" text="The Sturgiski come from the northern woods, just south of the icy Byalic Sea. For centuries they lived an isolated existence in the dark forests, their numbers kept in check by the deadly winters. But as the Empire expanded to fill out the Calradian continent, traders ventured into the woods in search of honey, bog iron, and most of all fur. Great towns sprung up on the network of bays and lakes that joined the Sturgian lands to the outside world, attracting fortune-seekers from the coast, the steppes, and the Nordlands. The princes and boyars of this land have now begun to turn their eyes outward, earning themselves for a reputation for their warlike approach to business and their businesslike approach to war. Much of the Sturgiski nobility traces their lineage to various Jumne adventurers that settled within the northern shores, such as the Gundaroving and the Vagiroving."/>
  <string id="str_faction_formal_name_for_culture.kannic.text" text="Kannic Politeia"/>
  <string id="str_faction_formal_name_for_culture.darshi.text" text="Darshi Empire"/>
  <string id="str_faction_formal_name_for_culture.geroia.text" text="Geroian Dukedom"/>
  <string id="str_faction_formal_name_for_culture.siri.text" text="Siri Queendom"/>
  <string id="str_faction_formal_name_for_culture.vakken.text" text="Vakken Realm"/>
  <string id="str_faction_formal_name_for_culture.nord.text" text="Jumne Realm"/>
  <string id="str_faction_formal_name_for_culture.bragantia.text" text="Bragantian County"/>
  <string id="IHhWB1aa" text="Darshi"/>
  <string id="str_culture_description.darshi.text" text="The Darshi are an ancient civilization that sprung by the Teyagh river and its sibling, the Nahr al-Kals. For millenia they have mastered trading far and wide, as well as farming grains and dates by the riverbanks, making use of any fertile land they could control. Their cities, built with great stone walls, withstood the raids of barbarians long before the Calradoi would pride themselves over their masonry. Currently, many of the originally northern Darshi settlements are now ruled by the Khuzait horselords, and the Darshianshahr finds itself in a defensive position."/>
  <string id="str_culture_rich_name.geroia.text" text="Geroiako"/>
  <string id="str_culture_description.geroia.text" text="Geroia lies in the heart of the Perassic sea, between the realms of the Calradoi and the Nahasawi. Long since separated from the Calradoi, the Geroians have leveraged their position to exerce hegemony over the sea trade. Though other realms are progressively abandoning slavery, the Geroians still widely practice it, selling and buying human as cattle far and wide with their ships. As the Geroians are restricted to their small, stony islands, such slave trade has been largely responsible for their proeminence. Before their rising to lords of the Perassic sea, the Geroians were largely ignorant of and ignored by their neighbors, content with raising sheep and farming grape for the distinct Geroiako white wine. They have for centuries supplied the Calradoi with their human 'products', who eagerly sought abundance of slaves to fuel their imperial expansion. The Geroiako cities, formerly independent republics, are bound together by their Ducxate - a recent arrangement, in face of the growing threats of the Nahasawi, their trade nemesis. Nevertheless, the duke's seat is not hereditary, and the Geroians still choose amongst themselves who to lead them. To this day, the Geroiako ports are a melting pot of cultures, where one can find traders and adventurers from lands most wihtin Calradia have never heard of. Yet, most of them are sure to not cause fuss, for they know any breach of Geroiako law will mean unceremonious enslavement, regardless of origin or station."/>
  <string id="str_culture_rich_name.siri.text" text="Siri"/>
  <string id="str_culture_description.siri.text" text="An ancient civilization born by the Aman river, known to the Nahasawi as Damar. The Siri, blessed by the fertility of the Aman, have mastered farming grain, dates and papyrus by the riverbanks such that their realm has great food abundance, despite being in the very core of the Nahasa desert. Unlike most cultures, they have organized themselves in a matriarchal system: women are supposed to lead families, and often a Siri queen leads the realm. Women also participate in war, though only as expert archers, with the men responsible for the brutality of melee. Many say only the Battaneid are a match for the Siri in terms of bowmanship. Yet, the Siri are reluctant to march into war, so long their domain was not trespassed. For the most part, Siri society is more interested in trade, farming and the worship of their gods: human-animal hybrids, for which they have much devotion. The Siri have also developed a particular talent for masonry: in particular, their unique, pyramid-shaped stone buildings instantly set them apart even from the Kannic, who are also able masons. Such stone structures are said to house the gods and queens of yore, and very seldom the Siri allow strangers into their sacred places."/>
  <string id="bHh03ob0" text="Vakken"/>
  <string id="str_culture_description.vakken.text" text="The Vakken are tribes natural to the Ircaran Wildlands, close by the Kachyar peninsula. Long ago, the Vakken and the Sturgians were closer kin. Though they increasingly distanced themselves, both tribes remained binded by their geography and faiths, which still share ancient traits. Unlike the Sturgians, however, the Vakken have never organized themselves in a kingdom. Their tribes scattered along the northern forests, all the way to the Karakaz river. The strongest tribes have built themselves forest-forts, but most Vakken still live by their tribe, deep in the woods. The woodland is their home, and sacred to their faith. No one can match the Vakken in hunting or foresting."/>
  <string id="str_culture_rich_name.nord.text" text="Jumne"/>
  <string id="str_culture_description.nord.text" text="The Jumne hail from a continent north of Calradia, their namesake. Masters of the longship, they have long since reached Calradia in independent incursions, be them for trading, settling or pillaging. Much like the Wilunding, with whom they share a distant ancestry, the presence of the Jumne has increasingly become a threat for those settled in Calradia. Most of their influence has been on the northern shores, largely in contact with the Sturgiskyy and Vakken tribes. Many Sturgiskyy dynasties can trace their origins to Jumne adventurers, such as the Gundaroving themselves, rulers of the Grand Principality of the Sturgiski. The saga of the Jumne has not yet finished, for there is still land to settle and kingdoms to pillage..."/>
  <string id="str_culture_rich_name.bragantia.text" text="Biscanian"/>
  <string id="str_culture_description.bragantia.text" text="The Biscan Isles have long been colonized by the Calradoi, not long after the founding of Charasea. In the height of the Empire's wealth and decadence, Calradoi aristocrats would cruise around the isles on pleasure-boats, and build private villas by the picturesque, cliffy shores. Brigantia was the center of the Isles' commerce, shipping fine wines, olives and products from west-over-seas, as well as a hotspot for northern furs and hides to be distributed in all directions. Common folk at the isles lived in relative peace, if not for the Jumne raiders when the Empire could not afford to patrol its shores, and mostly raised local cattle on the lush, grassy hills. With the Advent of the Wilunding, Imperial administration was supplanted by a migration of Massa rulers. Contrary to their reputation, these rulers conquered the Isles peacefully, and have merged with the locals. Folks of this mixed culture now call themselves Biscanjans, unifying their Calradoi legacy with the Massa language."/>
  <string id="str_culture_rich_name.kannic.text" text="Kannic"/>
  <string id="str_culture_description.kannic.text" text="The Kannic are an ancient Calradian civilization based on the southern coasts of the Perass and Jade seas. They first built Razih, and later proceeded to colonize the entire southern coast. They were renowned for their masonry and shipbuilding: before the Calradoi or the Geroiako dominated the seas, it was the domain of the Kannic triremes, adorned with the vines of their goddess. The Vine Goddess, Ailatyn, guides the Kannic both in trade and war. To other cultures, they seem avaricious, but to the Kannic, making profit is a holy endeavour. The remainings of the Kannic now lie at Lys - their last large colony -, for much of their original lands have been taken by the Nahasawi, something for which the Kannic carry deep resentment. Their pristine stone cities, they say, shall one day be cleansed from the hut-dwelling nomads."/>
  <string id="str_culture_rich_name.iltanlar.text" text="Iltanlar"/>
  <string id="str_culture_description.iltanlar.text" text="The Iltanlar are distant kin of the eastern Devseg. They have long inhabited the Sulan Dag mountains, east of Ortongard, and mastered living its dry, unforgiving climate. Unlike their mounted kin, the Iltanlar predominantly live on the mountains, and thus do not use or fight on horses as extensively. Their mountain god, Iltan, is said to protect their people, so long they live by sacred places - the mountains, their streams and woods. They have mastered the way of ironmongery, quarrying stone and building walls on such slopes, where they have founded their fortified cities. Their greatest city was Baltakhand - founded on the western slopes of the Sulan Daglar, and thus with better access to fertile land and water, making the city thrive. Unlike their eastern kin, the Iltanlar warfare relies on infantry, a necessary adaptation to their sloped homelands. Nevertheless, horse and cattle are still raised on the Sulan Dag plateaus, holding still great favor within their culture and economy."/>
  <string id="str_culture_rich_name.dryatic.text" text="Dryaticoi"/>
  <string id="str_culture_description.dryatic.text" text="Nearly exterminated by the Calradoi, the Dryaticoi were one of the largest Palaicoi tribes, the original inhabitants of the Imperial heartlands. The Dryaticoi inhabited the Dryatic mountain range, which touches the southwest shores of lake Lakonis. Having fought the Calradoi to the bitter end, the Dryaticoi society collapsed under the weight of the legions, who conquered and assimilated both Diathma and Epicrotea, leaving no trace of their traditions. Nevertheless, the remaining Dryaticoi secured themselves within the slopes of their mountains, waging a long and bloody war of attrition. Such is their ferocity that the Calradoi could not fully settle the Dryatic mountains, instead holding sparse, heavily garrisoned settlements within the region, as well as its borders. Much of the Dryaticoi culture was lost with the downfall of their society - nevertheless, remaining survivors hold still a mostly preserved language, as well as their gods of yore. And unlikely most gods within the continent, the Palaicoi gods demand the blood of their enemies."/>
  <string id="str_culture_rich_name.zendar.text" text="Zendari"/>
  <string id="str_culture_description.zendar.text" text="Zendar was once a Calradoi colony, its citizens counted among the lowest within Calradoi society. Eventually the pólis fell to its own devices, effectively making its administrator - the count - an independent ruler. Founded in the Calradoi border with the Battanians and Sturgians, the city has a long tradition of defensive measures, now embedded into its culture: expert crossbowmen, even compared to the Calradoi crossbowmen, man its walls against all sorts of raiding parties, including Jumne raiders from the sea. Greater than others is also Zendar's arena: a strong gladiatorial culture drives the pólis' economy, and its geographical position allows a plethora of different contestants to bid their wagers, making the Zendar tourneys one of the fiercest in the continent."/>
  <string id="str_culture_rich_name.lokti.text" text="Lokti"/>
  <string id="str_culture_description.lokti.text" text="Long ago, the Lokti migrated from the eastern steppes, north of the Devseg. In search of greener pastures, they stopped at their current position, the Lokti mountains at the root of the Byal peninsula. They use the stony slopes of the mountains to guard the back of their cities, and farm the green plains around the mountains, stocking food for the winter. Eventually, they mixed with the Vakken of the Karakaz forest, who taught them how to master the woods."/>
 </strings>
</base>
